Does the baby need a break?
Thank you.
- Please.
This is a local beer.
Welcome to the faculty,
Professor Wong.
Thank you.
How was your trip?
Not too much jet lag?
It's not that bad.
Wonderful.
I am your assistant,
also your interpreter if required.
I am doing my doctorate in neurology.
I have studied your work.
Maybe we'd rather speak English?
Is my Cantonese that bad?
I'm sorry about that.
I cheated and claimed
I speak Cantonese.
But I only speak it to my grandma.
Her Cantonese is not bad.
I am a big fan
of your research work.
I will do my best.
Thank you.
This is a local specialty.
Hello?
I'm fine.
Yes, I'm fine.
I need a projector tomorrow.
I have already written to the university.
I can do it on my own.
That's very kind of you.
See you tomorrow.
You've probably seen the model many times before.
After all, it stands
the central theme of your studies.
For some, it will occupy them for the rest of their lives.
Then please tell me what it is.
A human brain.
Well, actually it is
a nice colorful piece of plastic.
Everything we research
should be viewed in a similar way.
Research is nothing more
than a series of experiments,
metaphors for the phenomena
of the world.
Please switch off all
electronic devices.
I'll show you something.
You are now
focused on this object.
The light is bright,
you are not exposed to any other
visual stimuli.
This is the default setting
of the adult brain.
We call it "Spotlight Consciousness".
We perceive the world around us
in a sequence
quicker, more focused moments.
It was recently thought
that babies are the same,
only on a more primitive level.
But our research
prove the opposite.
Pass the ball,
wherever you want.
Next.
You see,
in this gently moving glow
are the boundaries between
the seen and the unseen,
Noticed and unnoticed
fluent.
This is not about limitation,
Nor is it about separation.
It is about
being part of a continuity.
What you are experiencing now is what we,
other researchers and me,
imagine,
how babies perceive the world.
We call this "Lantern Consciousness".
When we adults
concentrate on something,
parts of our brain switch off,
that are not directly involved.
Concentrate means
in our case, to exclude.
When babies encounter something new,
or interesting things,
they do exactly the opposite.
They do not switch off.
Most regions of their brain
are activated.
They observe the new phenomenon
in its entirety,
in every conceivable context.
Let's take a look at this example:
a 50-year-old man
and a 6-month-old child.
We have given both
a completely new task,
which required her undivided attention
required.
We compared their brain activity
before and during the task.
We had expected similar changes.
We were completely wrong.
Do you see?
The difference is astounding.
The baby's brain waves are similar to those
of people in deep meditation.
Or under the influence of certain
psychedelic substances.
You could say
that babies are high all the time.
Well, this is the state
scientists hope for
in their rare moments of intuition.
In view of the
worsening COVID-19 situation
individuals and organizations
and organizations,
to fight the virus together
and support Hong Kong.
... while this part here is the cortex.
It distinguishes us from the animals
and makes us
the most evolved species on earth.
What do you do when you want to
you want to get in touch with,
but don't have a common language?
They are curious,
but you can't ask any questions.
If you are a scientist,
you are lucky.
You can do an experiment.
To start with, I have chosen
the mimosa.
She has become famous for one single reason
reason she became famous.
It can do the following:
It is one of the few plants
that allows us to analyze its reactions within
of a human time frame
to observe.
That is pure coincidence,
but we are thrilled about it.
And that's why we say:
Yes, of course it's intelligent,
because it does something.
This is how the mimosa
the "intelligent" plant,
simply because of this coincidence.
Because of the relative proximity to the time periods
in which we live.
But it turned out
that the mimosa learns,
remembers,
weighs up their options
and makes decisions.
Chassé
...skip!
and leap.
I work with babies,
until they start talking,
and since we have no verbal feedback,
the wildest assumptions circulate in the scientific community
the wildest conjectures.
Well, to be honest,
we can only guess today.
It is a relatively new field of research.
A bit like mine.
Exactly.
And that's why I contacted you.
Thank you for your time.
But with pleasure.
To come back to my question:
Would you like to be my mentor?
That's pretty arrogant of me,
I am a total amateur in your field,
if at all!
What I want to test,
is not very complex.
As you said in your presentation,
What if they were to
as we observe them?
I would like to find out...
- Are you in Hong Kong?
Do you have access to the laboratory?
- No.
You need material.
I'm stuck on an empty campus
somewhere in Germany.
Me too, but at home
with a three-year-old.
I'm going crazy,
because I can't work.
We had to close everything.
I shouldn't even be here.
I just snuck in here.
I actually have to go into the greenhouse.
It's not quite clear to me yet,
what you're getting at, but let's see.
Can I call you back on my cell phone?
- Please do so.
Hello!
The sensors
are now working properly.
Thanks for the advice.
I am currently trying to
to create basic references.
Two sample groups that
relate to similar experiences.
Why not?
But then you have to live with it,
that the results
are scientifically inaccurate.
But you know that yourself.
Of course.
This is our ginkgo.
Not quite as splendid as yours.
It's a boy.
Probably yours too.
What makes you think that?
It is unusual
to plant female trees in gardens.
Too close to the people.
- And why?
They have a very unpleasant odor.
In the fall, when the fruit is ripe,
they stink like vomit.
Interesting.
Smell it for yourself.
Good idea.
I always ask myself,
how they endure the loneliness.
I see in botanical gardens
just a bunch of lonely souls,
without a chance of a social life.
Would they not make contact with other species
around them?
No.
They must be bored to death
or are depressed.
And that's where you work!
- That's how it is.
I am a very bad person.
It is a female.
That is bold.
Then she's not so lonely.
There must be males around them.
Not really.
This is the only ginkgo here.
I have checked.
- Strange.
The poor.
I could send you seeds.
Seeds?
These are living fossils,
gymnosperms.
You probably know that.
- I don't.
Their sex life is pretty archaic.
Very impractical, actually.
Hello, Professor Wong.
Hello.
I just wanted to know how you were doing.
Do you feel lonely?
Lonely?
No. And you?
We are all doing well, thank you.
It must be depressing
alone on the large campus.
Because of the loneliness.
- It works.
Sorry!
Sorry.
Are you calling about something specific?
Indeed.
The university called me.
Because of...
They're worried about you,
They want me to visit you.
I'm fine.
They shouldn't worry.
I hope it's not a problem,
that I'm occupying the guest room.
I've been asked to talk to you...
About what?
There was a complaint.
Let me read it to you:
Professor Wong displays
displays disturbing behavior.
He should refrain from doing so in future...
That's probably enough, sorry.
It's embarrassing to bother you
to bother you about this stupid complaint.
That is completely absurd!
You're a good girl, my sweetie.
I'm sorry, he's fed up,
of always being at home.
Where were we?
- Well...
I am looking for comparable experiences.
I started with rain for them
and showers for me.
Then you should have
drink in the shower!
I'll be right with you.
Why don't you try psylocibine?
Or mescaline.
That's difficult to get here.
In the greenhouse perhaps?
Could be.
Wait, I'll show you someone.
He doesn't like me very much.
I have invaded his realm.
You are very sweet.
I need material
for my next experiment.
You might find this in the neurology lab.
Mr. Wong...
I can't help you.
With your chip card...
No.
I'm sorry,
You're putting me in an awkward position.
Their research was put on hold.
I mean the research,
which is why I was hired.
Not that...
This is the answering machine of
Alice Sauvage. Speak now.
Good, very good.
"Good luck with the sperm. Alice"
In loving memory
of Karl Baumgartner
Subtitling: SUBS Hamburg
Mireille Onon